Earlier in our course they talked about the project lifecycle and the project management lifecycle.
Recall that the project management lifecycle was the idea of initiating planning executing monitoring
controlling and closing.
There are some other characteristics here of the project management lifecycle and the project lifecycle
there's almost an overlap in how the work is planned and how the work is delivered and the Pinback eyed
6 edition will have to address what's called both predictive and adaptive life cycles.
So as we move through the Pinback guide you're going to see little sections where gets has a consideration
for an adaptive environment.
So let's nail down the difference between predictive and adaptive.
First off a predictive life cycle is typically what we have in a construction environment where it's
plan driven right know everything up front or most things up front in order to get started.
So it's a pretty good idea of where we're going to get to the end of the construction project predictive
life cycles are also known as a waterfall approach where we start at a high level and we do work.
We go to the next phase and we do work and down and down it goes.
So it is a waterfall moving closer and closer to the finish.
So it's a predictive lifecycle or a waterfall approach.
It predicts the project life cycle and construction upfront we can identify the phases that will move
us from the foundation all the way to closing the project.
So it predicts the life cycle in a predictive life cycle typically changes to the scope are tightly
controlled that we are a bit change adverse not to say that changes don't happen in predictive.
Just generally we try to capture all of the requirements up front and then once we're in motion we become
change adverse then we have what's called an iterative and incremental life cycles iterative in incremental
life cycles and we really go through iterations where phases are repeated through iterations iterations
create deliverables the detailed scope is what's created for each iteration and changes to the project
are expected.
What's the difference though between iterative and incremental.
Both of these are similar.
They go through phases that are repeated over and over and over incremental though means that I give
you things in increments.
So I'm going to create a piece of software that has the limited functionality and then we'll go through
the whole process again.
And we're going to add on in an increment that now you can print from that software and then we go through
it again and now and another increment you're able to you know send text messages from the software
or whatever it may be.
So it or iterative or just simply you go through iterations to create in the final product.
Incremental means you get deliverables in increments.
So they're similar but different.
I got one just like that only different.
All right.
So incremental are tiny increments for deliverables and adaptive lifecycle can be iterative or incremental.
You probably know adaptive if you've worked in scrum or XP XP or extreme programming or lean.
Those are all examples of adaptive with scrum being one of the most common or ad Jayal.
So this what we're looking at here in this picture is a Conboy on board.
So a combo on board shows where do we start with the number of stories.
Stories are requirements user stories what's in motion.
So what are we doing.
What's in progress.
What's going through testing all the way over to what's finished.
So this is called a sign.
We'll see this a couple of times but this is one of the things that we can use in an adaptive environment
adaptive environments are change driven.
Well we don't know everything that we're going to create at the beginning of the project like a predictive
lifecycle.
So what we have an adaptive and this is on general terms I know there's different flavors here but generally
we have what's called a product backlog.
That's all of the requirements and a product owner will prioritize with the team what's most important.
The team then we'll say okay over the next two weeks or four weeks the next iteration sometimes called
the sprint.
This is what we can get done.
I can get done this much work in the next four weeks.
So they take the most important items and they go and work on those items while they're working on those
items there can be no changes that we're focused on only these items.
Well we're done with those items.
We're done with that iteration we do some reviews sometimes called the retrospective and then we go
back with the product owner and the project team and then the product owner now has a chance to reorder
the list of items in that backlog and even add to it.
And so you go through these iterations to continue to take the requirements and do the work to take
the requirements do the work and the requirements can shift in priority before each sprint or before
each iteration.
So that's kind of the high level picture of adaptive we we'll see that a few more times.
And yes you'll have a few questions on that on your PMI exam.
So it's rapid iterations of project work backlog requirement and we expect changes to happen.
It's just part of it.
We don't know everything up front.
So we were adaptive to change so we welcome change in an adaptive lifecycle.
So we have predictive and we have adaptive and there's two variations there iterative and incremental.
Okay good job.
Those are three new terms for you I guess really for two terms.
If you think about it.
Okay I'll see you in the next lecture.
Keep moving forward you're making great progress.